Contact

mdsn85@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-saad-688874179 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

c#

JavaScript

Certifications

Data Analysis

DAT263x: Introduction to Artificial Intelligence (AI)

Introduction to Mobile Solution Development for the Enterprise

Mohammad Saad

Full Stack Engineer: .Net (ASP.NET, MVC, API, Javascript, CSS, HTML) MEAN Stack (MongoDB, Express , Angular)
United Arab Emirates

Summary

Experienced software engineer who loves Developing Software Solution for business and society. I have a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and Software Development. Skilled in analyze requirement, design business process, code business model and design easy functional user interface.

Experience

entrepreneur Hybrid Mobile Developer June 2019 - September 2019 (4 months) Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Use Case: They hired me to develop mobile application to connect Truck driver with Operation dept. and call center, to render all tasks instantly and efficiently, then generate invoice after task completed, these invoices must be compatible with existing accounting software

- I develop Hybrid mobile application using Ionic framework, Angular and firebase.
- Designs and develops User Interface for mobile applications using Ionic , JavaScript,and CSS.
- Design database and develop API for data request
- Design architect and manage of Etisalat Cloud Services

Entrepreneur

Full Stack Engineer

March 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Use Case: CRM software Manage customers' relationship from leads to invoice with one integrated software CRM.. http://www.skipscrm.com/

 Designs and develops User Interface for web applications using JavaScript, CSS, and HTML5.

- Design database and develop sql queries
- applies Net Web API's for mobile application
- Design and code high-quality web application using Microsoft, C#, and JavaScript library like(jquery, ajax, ...).
- Design and code high-quality hybrid mobile application using lonic platform , Angular and firebase.
- Design architect and manage of Etisalat Cloud Services
- Design and implement .NET Microservices: Architecture for Containerized .NET Applications

Saad Al hamadi Legal Office Dotnet Developer April 2018 - December 2018 (9 months) Dubai

Software for legal offiUse Case: Legal Assistant Software is developed to manage law firms and communicate with their clients easily and efficiently The legal assistant emulates the records of lawyers' offices and adds business intelligence.

- Designs and develops User Interface for web applications using JavaScript,
 CSS, and HTML5.
- Design database and develop sql queries
- Met with the company's clients; developed the design framework for the respective websites by collating information on the clients; business goals and objectives.
- Conducted comprehensive research covering the industry, target market, and financial costs for the purpose of creating a budget for the project.
- Presented clients with a series of mockups for the website.
- Performs regular audits to check on website data security, outdated applications and programs, and site functionality.

се

Prism

SAP Project Coordinator
May 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 8 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

project coordinator to be the liaison between the project manager of Client company and Prism

- Collect requirement from customer
- Configure master data to SAP backend

• Schedule and follow up consultation meeting

Mds

Dotnet Developer May 2010 - April 2014 (4 years)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Design and Developing in house ERP for company using Visual Studio & .net
- Testing and quality control for new model implemented in ERP

syria tel Dotnet Developer January 2009 - February 2010 (1 year 2 months) Syria

• Handled the task of developing new software to reward Syriatell customer (new form , design database)

Education

Tishreen University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering · (2003 - 2018)